Guide to the Rice PRIDE records, 1981-2013 UA 326
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice PRIDE records
1981-2013
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 326
1.5 Linear Feet 2 boxes
These records include the daily business, projects, and publicity for Rice PRIDE student group. (2 boxes)
Biographical / Historical
In 1979, future Houston mayor Annise Parker gave Rice professor, Dr. Chandler Davidson, a note with a phone number on it. He then called and heard a man say: "the gay students on campus want to form an officially recognized student group." Davidson agreed and sponsored the group, which took the name The Rice Gay/Lesbian Support Group (RG/LSG). The organization maintained this title until 1986 when it was renamed Gays and Lesbians of Rice (GALOR).
To be more inclusive, GALOR became Pride in 1994. The members wanted to include not only gays and lesbians, but also bisexuals, transgendered people, and allies. During the 2003/2004 academic year, some Pride members created a new group called GATHER (GLBTQAs Advancing Towards a Harmonious Environment at Rice). The impetus for creating GATHER came from the Coach Ken Hatfield controversy in which the football coach made public statements about how he might treat homosexual players. Where Pride served a social function on campus, GATHER had a more social activist thrust. GATHER even had a meeting space in the Wellness Center. In September 2007, Pride and GATHER joined to become Queers and Allies.
Queers and Allies sponsored GLBTQ-themed film showings, sponsors speakers, and organized an annual drag show at Willy's Pub. In 2017, the newly created Queer Resource Center and Queers and Allies joined to become Rice PRIDE.
Scope and Contents
This record group charts the history of Rice PRIDE through correspondence, minutes, special projects, and memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
Some materials are restricted due to the sensitive information contained therein. Each restricted folder is labeled. Access to these records requires written permission from the Office of the Dean of Undergraduates. Contact Woodson staff for instructions. Materials will be restricted until 2062.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Amanda Mills and Jessica Williams in 2013. Materials donated by Laura Sawyer in 2014.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Social life and customs; LGBTQ people
Document Types
memorabilia; photographs
- Series I: Alphabetical files, 1981-2013, 169063
  - Affiliated organizations, 1987-2002, n.d.; 169064 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution, 1980, 2012; 169065 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Restricted), 1981, 1993-2003, n.d.; 169066 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial, 1992-2003; 169067 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hate Crimes Prevention Act petition, October 1998; 169068 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memorabilia (Drag Show Tickets), 2005, n.d.; 169069 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and Agenda (Restricted), 1992-2012; 169070 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Coming Out Project, 1992, n.d.; 169071 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National speakers and conferences, 1995-2003, n.d.; 169072 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newsclippings, 1995-2013, n.d.; 169073 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, 1992, 1993; 169074 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Publicity, 1981-2013, n.d.; 169075 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Purity Test, 1990s; 169076 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rice Ally Program, 1995; 169077 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II: Photographs and Scrapbooks, 169078
  - Photographs, 1990s-2000s; 169080 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - GATHER scrapbook, 2004; 169081 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series III: T-Shirts, 169079
  - Light blue RG/LSG v-neck T-Shirt with crest on back, ca. 1982; 169082 (Box 2, Item 1)
  - Black Queers and Allies T-Shirt, 2011; 169083 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Centennial Pride Parade T-Shirt, ca. 2012; 169084 (Box 2, Item 3)
  - Pink Queers and Allies T-Shirt, 169085 (Box 2, Item 4)
  - The Rice Gay/Lesbian Support Group T-Shirt (Box 2, Item 5)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Donated to Rice by Annise Parker, '78.